National Congress of Neighborhood Women Records, 1974-1999
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION 1974-1996
  - Funding agencies
    - New York City-Department of Employment-Comprehensive Employment Training Act (CETA)
      - Legal cases
        - NCNW v. City of New York, 1979-80
          - Demonstration: memoranda, notes, flyers, and songs, 1980 (Box 55, Folder 13)
            [See also SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS]
          - Project Open Doors subcontractors: meetings, program descriptions, and correspondence, 1980, undated (Box 55, Folder 14-15)
          - Miscellaneous: printed material, 1979-80, undated (Box 55, Folder 16-17)
      - Job Training Partnership Act (JPTA)
        - General: correspondence, meetings, and contracts, 1982-84 (including material re: transition from CETA) (Box 56, Folder 1-4)
        - Legal case: correspondence, publicity, and petition, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 5-6)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Information Exchange workshop, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 7)
          - Conference on Welfare Reform, 1987 (Box 56, Folder 8)
        - Discretionary funds, 1988-89 (Box 56, Folder 9-10)
    - New York Community Trust (Box 56, Folder 11)
    - New York Council for the Humanities (Box 56, Folder 12)
    - New York State Community Action Program (CAP) (Box 56, Folder 13)
    - New York State Council for the Arts (Box 56, Folder 14)
    - New York State CSBG (Box 56, Folder 15)
    - New York State-Department of Social Services (DSS) (Box 56, Folder 16-18)
    - New York State-DSS (Box 57, Folder 1-3)
    - New York Times Foundation (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Norman Foundation (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - North Star (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Office of Economic Opportunity (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Pfizer Foundation (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Playboy Foundation (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Presbyterian Church (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Rockefeller Brothers Fund (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Rockefeller Foundation (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - Satellite Program Development Fund (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Scherman Foundation (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Scientists' Institute for Public Information (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Skaggs Foundation (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Stern Foundation (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - United States Department of Labor (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - United Way Emergency Food and Shelter Program (FEMA) (Box 57, Folder 19-26)
    - Urban Crime Prevention Program (Box 57, Folder 27)
    - Vincent Astor Foundation (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - VISTA (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Volunteer Urban Consulting Group, Inc. (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Volunteer Demonstration Program (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - Windum Fund (Box 58, Folder 5)
    - Women's Education Equity Act Program (WEEA), US Dept of HEW (Box 58, Folder 6-14)
- SERIES II. PROGRAMS 1975-1996
  - Support services
    - General: proposal, 1981 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Childcare
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Education; Employment-Employment and Training Program- Family Child Care Provider Training; Youth programs-"You Can Community School"]
      - General: correspondence, lists, and printed material, 1980-87, undated (Box 59, Folder 2)
      - Proposal (Neighborhood Child Care Network), 1982 (Box 59, Folder 3)
      - Edu-Care Center: correspondence, regulations, and form, 1991 (Box 59, Folder 4)
      - Tot lot, 1984 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      - Resources
        - NCNW Resource and Directory Guide, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 6)
        - Childcare providers: lists (Box 59, Folder 7)
        - Child development and safety (Box 59, Folder 8)
        - Child abuse (Box 59, Folder 9)
        - Non-Sexist Child Development Project (Women's Action Alliance project) (Box 59, Folder 10)
        - Play Streets (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Counseling and referral
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Education-College Program; Employment-Job Development; and Leadership]
      - General: descriptions, and proposal, undated (Box 59, Folder 12-13)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1987 (Box 59, Folder 14)
      - Meetings, 1988 (Box 59, Folder 15)
      - Report, 1986 (Box 59, Folder 16)
      - Procedures (Box 59, Folder 17-19)
      - Social Work interns
        - General (Box 59, Folder 20)
        - Columbia University (Box 59, Folder 21)
        - Fordham (Box 59, Folder 22)
        - Hunter College (Box 59, Folder 23)
        - New York University (Box 59, Folder 24-26)
        - Stony Brook (SUNY) (Box 59, Folder 27-29)
      - Counselor training, 1979 (Box 59, Folder 30)
  - Community and economic development
    - Women in Neighborhoods Project
      - General: correspondence, memoranda, minutes, proposals, and printed material, 1979-87 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
      - Survey
        - Correspondence and notes (Box 60, Folder 3)
        - Questionnaires, forms, form letters, and project descriptions (Box 60, Folder 4)
        - List of survey participants (Box 60, Folder 5)
      - Conference, Washington, D.C., 1979
        - Planning (Box 60, Folder 6-9)
        - Conference packet: program, memoranda, brochures, and printed material (Box 60, Folder 10)
        - Conference papers (Box 60, Folder 11-13)
      - Report ("Neighborhood Women: Putting It Together"): published report, brochure, summary, drafts, notes, and printed material, 1980 (Box 60, Folder 14-22)
    - Women in Poverty Project
      - Administration
        - General: proposals, brochure, project summaries, reports, timelines, and budget, 1980-82 (Box 61, Folder 1-5)
        - Job descriptions (Box 61, Folder 6)
        - Correspondence, 1980-82, undated (Box 61, Folder 7)
        - Dutchess County primary contact list, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 8)
        - Meetings: minutes, 1980-82, undated (Box 61, Folder 9)
        - Advisory board (Box 61, Folder 10-11)
        - Area policy board (Box 61, Folder 12-13)
        - Newspaper clippings, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 14)
        - Reports, 1981 (Box 61, Folder 15)
        - Articles, undated (Box 61, Folder 16)
        - Miscellaneous printed material (Box 61, Folder 17)
        - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 61, Folder 18)
      - Planning conferences: agendas, correspondence, publicity, and notes, 1981-82 (Box 61, Folder 19-21)
      - Dutchess County Exit Audit Conference: minutes, 1980 (Box 61, Folder 22)
      - Phase I (Information gathering)
        - Questionnaires
          - Community Action Agencies (CAA): correspondence, drafts, and research material (Box 61, Folder 23)
          - Community Action Programs (C.A.P.): lists, correspondence, and responses (Box 61, Folder 24-26)
        - Training manual (Box 61, Folder 27-28)
      - Phase II (Training)
        - General: conference summaries, planning, registration, and financial, 1982 (Box 62, Folder 1-4)
        - Conferences: agendas, correspondence, invitations, contacts, registration, financial, lists, and notes, 1982
          - South Bronx (Box 62, Folder 5-14)
          - Rockland County (Box 62, Folder 15-19)
          - S.C.O.P.E., Glasboro College, N.J. (Box 62, Folder 20-27)
          - P.E.A.C.E., Syracuse (Box 62, Folder 28)
          - Essex County (Box 62, Folder 29-32)
          - Puerto Rico (Box 62, Folder 33-34)
          - Virgin Islands (Box 62, Folder 35)
    - National Resource and Policy Analysis Center, Washington, D.C.
      [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Development-CSA]
      - General: histories, descriptions, and lease, 1980-81 (Box 63, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and memoranda, 1979-82 (Box 63, Folder 2-3)
      - Planning: correspondence, meetings, notes, and miscellaneous, 1979-80, undated (Box 63, Folder 4-15)
      - Proposals, applications, and correspondence, 1980-81 (Box 63, Folder 16-19)
      - Reports (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Staff logs, undated (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Workshop: flyer (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Publications (Box 64, Folder 6-8)
      - Subjects
        - Beacon College (Box 64, Folder 9)
        - Housing Task Force: Memoranda and report, 1981 (Box 64, Folder 10)
        - Resources: A Neighborhood Compendium, 1982 (Box 64, Folder 11)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 64, Folder 12-14)
    - Community Development Institute
      - First Institute (Planning for "Dialogue") (Box 64, Folder 15-24)
      - Annual Institute proposal and drafts, 1990, undated (Box 65, Folder 1-3)
      - Annual Summer Institutes on Women and Community Development, Grailville, Ohio, 1992-95 (Box 65, Folder 4-12)
      - Subject files: articles and printed material (Box 65, Folder 13)
    - Dialogues on Community Development and Female Poverty
      - General: proposals, summaries, correspondence, printed material, and notes, 1983-84, undated (Box 65, Folder 14-21)
      - New York State Dialogues
        - Pawling: program, forms, background, and follow-up correspondence, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 1-3)
        - Syracuse: agenda, correspondence, publicity, and background, 1984-88, undated (Box 66, Folder 4-5)
        - Planning meetings, 1983-84 (Box 66, Folder 6)
        - Local programs (demonstration district): correspondence, lists, and community objectives, 1985, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
        - Community Services Block Grant Program, 1983-85 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Feminization of Poverty Hearings, 1984
      [See also Leadership - National training - Syracuse]
      - General: publicity, schedules, registration material, correspondence, and minutes, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 11-13)
      - Hearings: transcripts, 1984 (Box 66, Folder 14-16)
      - Background
        - Writings by NCNW, 1983-84, undated (Box 66, Folder 17)
        - NY State: reports and statistics, 1984, undated (Box 66, Folder 18-19)
        - National: reports and statistics, 1981-84, undated (Box 66, Folder 20)
        - Legislation pertaining to women, 1978, 1983-84 (Box 66, Folder 21)
        - General: papers, reports, articles, clippings, printed material, and notes (Box 66, Folder 22-25)
    - Conference: "Women in Community Development: Forging a National Alliance with International Linkages" (co-sponsored by Overseas Education Fund), 1986
      - Overview (Box 67, Folder 1)
      - Planning: meetings and notes (Box 67, Folder 2-3)
      - Invitations: correspondence and mailing lists (Box 67, Folder 4)
      - Conference packet (Box 67, Folder 5)
      - Evaluations (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Subject files
      - Community development
        - General: printed material (Box 67, Folder 7)
        - Women in community development: printed material (Box 67, Folder 8)
        - Articles and papers
          - "Community Development: Visions and Strategies," by Susan Saegert (Box 67, Folder 9)
          - "The Emerging Women-in-Development Movement," by Rona F. Feit (Box 67, Folder 10)
          - "Factors Which Enhance the Participation of Women in Urban Neighborhood Social Life," by Sandra Schoenberg and Irene Dabrowski (Box 67, Folder 11)
          - "Mapping Community Capacity," by John. L. McKnight (Box 67, Folder 12)
          - "Organizing Women: Gender, Class and Community Organizations," by Susana T. Fried (Box 67, Folder 13)
          - "A Report of the Monitors: A Citizen's Panel Looks at HUD's Community Development Strategies Evaluation" (Box 67, Folder 14)
          - "Research Needs and Guidelines on Women's Issues: Planning, Housing and Community Development," by Jacqueline Leavitt (Box 67, Folder 15)
      - Economic development
        - General: printed material (Box 67, Folder 16)
        - Papers
          - "Economic Development as if Women Mattered," by Sara Gould (Box 67, Folder 17)
          - "The Economic Justice Issue: The Community Development Position of the NCNW" (Box 67, Folder 18)
          - "The Impact of the World Economic Crisis On Women in the U.S. Discussion Paper: The Social-Cultural Sector," by Rona F. Feit (Box 67, Folder 19)
          - "Neighborhood Women's Agenda for Economic Development in New York State," by Ronnie Feit (Box 67, Folder 20)
          - "Problems Poor and Working Class Women Have with 'Economic Development," by Ronnie Feit (Box 67, Folder 21)
          - "Recommendations for a Research Design to Study the Underground Economic Activities of Women in Williamsburg/Greenpoint," by Rachel B. Pfeffer (Box 67, Folder 22)
          - "Sustainable Human Development and Economic Growth," by Denis Benn (Box 67, Folder 23)
          - "Women and Enterprise," by June A. Sekera (Box 67, Folder 24)
          - "Women: The Fifth World," by Elise Boulding (Box 67, Folder 25)
      - Female poverty
        - Papers
          - "The Social Change Issue of Women and Poverty," by Karen Vanderborgh (Box 67, Folder 26)
          - "Welfare and Self-Employment," by Kathryn Keeley (Box 67, Folder 27)
          - "Welfare Mothers Earn Their Way," by Theresa Funiciello (Box 67, Folder 28)
          - "Women, Faith, and Economic Justice," edited by Jackie M. Smith (Box 67, Folder 29)
          - "Women in Poverty: A Challenge To CED," by Sara Gould (Box 67, Folder 30)
  - Education
    - General
      - Publicity: flyers, articles, and descriptions (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence, 1978-88, undated (Box 68, Folder 2-4)
      - Education committee: correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes, and agenda materials, 1977-79, undated (Box 68, Folder 5-8)
      - Education Project Board: correspondence, minutes, and notes, 1985 (Box 68, Folder 9)
      - Coordinators, 1980-84, undated (Box 68, Folder 10-11)
      - Reports, 1975-86 (Box 68, Folder 12-14)
      - Funding: correspondence, proposals, and budget, 1975-86 (Box 68, Folder 15-25)
      - Job descriptions and resumes (Box 69, Folder 1-2)
      - Miscellaneous: notes and printed material (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Curriculum development: correspondence, proposals, papers, minutes, schedules, course descriptions, and resources, 1975-87, undated (Box 69, Folder 4-13)
    - Course materials: syllabi, study guides, reading lists, and handouts, 1974-77, undated (Box 69, Folder 14-17)
    - Course evaluations, 1985-87, undated (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - College Program
      - General
        - Publicity: flyers, articles, newsletter, and miscellaneous descriptions, 1975-84, undated (Box 69, Folder 19-22)
        - Papers
          - "College for Neighborhood Women," by Terry Haywoode, undated (Box 69, Folder 23)
          - "College Model," by Jan Peterson, undated (Box 69, Folder 24)
          - "College Program," by Laura Scanlon, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 25)
          - "Planning to Meet the Needs of Women...," by Haywoode & Scanlon, undated (Box 69, Folder 26)
          - "Knowledge, Skill & Power:...," by Staton, Haywoode, Giordana, and Peterson, undated (Box 69, Folder 27)
          - Miscellaneous (Box 69, Folder 28)
        - Orientation (Box 69, Folder 29)
      - Schools and programs
        - Carroll Gardens College Program: publicity, description, and questionnaire; correspondence, meetings, reports, contract, schedules, and notes, 1978-81, undated (Box 70, Folder 1-11)
        - Ridgewood/Bushwick: correspondence and description, 1979-86, undated (Box 70, Folder 12-13)
        - Pittsburgh Sister School, undated (Box 70, Folder 14)
        - Williamsburg-Greenpoint-Northside Colloquium: proposals and descriptions, undated (Box 70, Folder 15)
        - Women Studies College, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 16)
        - Empire State College: correspondence, and program descriptions (Box 70, Folder 17)
        - Hunter College, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 18)
          [See also Counseling-Social Work interns]
        - LaGuardia Community College program
          - General: program descriptions and printed material, 1977 (Box 70, Folder 19)
          - Correspondence, 1978-79 (Box 70, Folder 20)
          - Curriculum, 1976 (Box 70, Folder 21)
          - Policies "battle": correspondence, statements, and publicity, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 22)
          - Meetings with coordinators of Off-Campus Programs: minutes and course proposal, 1980 (Box 70, Folder 23)
          - Brooklyn Public Library: survey, report, and correspondence, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 24)
        - Old Westbury (SUNY) (Box 70, Folder 25)
      - Association for Community Based Education (ACBE): correspondence and conference material, 1986-87 (Box 70, Folder 26-27)
      - Students: commencements, reunion, student organizations, statistics, and lists, 1977-87 (Box 71, Folder 1-12)
    - Adult Education
      [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-World of Work; Housing and tenants-Public housing tenants training; and Youth-You Can School]
      - General: schedule, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 13)
      - Board of Education: correspondence and printed material, 1985-87 (Box 71, Folder 14)
      - Programs
        - Adult literacy, 1986-87, undated (Box 71, Folder 15)
        - ESL students, 1988-89, undated (Box 71, Folder 16)
        - GED, 1984-85 (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Community Education Resource Center (CERC): correspondence and printed material, 1985-87 (Box 71, Folder 18-19)
    - Conferences
      - "Knowledge for Whom? Education as Culture Shock," 1976 (Box 71, Folder 20)
      - National Training Institute
        - Correspondence and programs, 1979 (Box 71, Folder 21-22)
        - Publicity, proposals, reports, lists, financial, and planning materials, 1979 (Box 72, Folder 1-16)
    - Resources and subject files
      - Area colleges (Box 72, Folder 17)
      - Community Education Project (Box 72, Folder 18)
      - Literacy (Box 72, Folder 19)
      - Miscellaneous education resources (Box 73, Folder 1)
      - Training-writing (Box 73, Folder 2)
      - Training materials, general (Box 73, Folder 3-8)
      - Women in education (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Employment
    - General
      - Meetings (early planning): minutes, notes, 1976 (includes Employment, Leadership, Counseling, and Education planning) (Box 74, Folder 1)
      - Proposals
        - Community Job Assistance Project, 1982 (Box 74, Folder 2)
        - Comprehensive Employment Opportunity Support Center, circa 1988 (Box 74, Folder 3)
        - Women in Apprenticeship, circa 1977 (Box 74, Folder 4)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 74, Folder 5)
      - School Settlement Association: correspondence, reports, subcontractors, personnel practices, and notes, 1976-79, undated (Box 74, Folder 6-14)
    - Project Open Doors
      [See also SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS-Women's Funding Coalition; and SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Development-NYC-CETA]
      - General: contract, correspondence, and financial, 1976-81 (Box 74, Folder 15-21)
      - General (continued): meetings, reports, staff, and procedures, 1978-81, undated (Box 75, Folder 1-19)
      - Publicity and publications: correspondence, press statements, descriptions,brochure, articles, newsletters, and manuscript ("Those Women") (Box 75, Folder 20-26)
      - Participating organizations (subcontractors)
        - General: lists, evaluations, field representatives, and form (Box 76, Folder 1-6)
        - Asian American Women's Communication Network (Box 76, Folder 7)
        - Bronx Household Technicians (Box 76, Folder 8)
        - Brooklyn in Touch (Box 76, Folder 9)
        - Brooklyn Women's Martial Arts (Box 76, Folder 10)
        - Carroll Gardens Neighborhood Women (Box 76, Folder 11)
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Education]
        - Committee to Aid Women in Crisis (Box 76, Folder 12)
        - Community Cable Center of Washington Heights, Inwood and Marble Hill (Box 76, Folder 13-15)
        - The Council of Asian American Women (Box 76, Folder 16)
        - Creative Women's Collective (Box 76, Folder 17)
        - Downtown Welfare Advocacy Center (Box 76, Folder 18)
        - Feminist Health Works (Box 77, Folder 1-2)
        - The Foundation for the Community of Artists (Box 77, Folder 3-6)
        - Graphic Help Project (Box 77, Folder 7-8)
        - Health Right (Box 77, Folder 9)
        - Hope for Youth (Box 77, Folder 10)
        - Jane Addams Center (Box 77, Folder 11)
        - Midmarch Associates (Box 77, Folder 12)
        - NCNW (Box 77, Folder 13)
        - National Gay Task Force (Box 77, Folder 14)
        - National Organization for Women (Box 77, Folder 15-19)
        - New York Feminist Federal Credit Union (Box 78, Folder 1)
        - New York Women Against Rape (Box 78, Folder 2)
        - Project Greenhope (Box 78, Folder 3-6)
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment and Training Program]
        - Publishing Training Institute for Women (Majority Report) (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Scapegoat (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - Thirteenth Moon (Box 78, Folder 9)
        - Union Center for Women (Box 78, Folder 10)
        - Village Visiting Center (Box 78, Folder 11)
        - Women in the Trades (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - Women Make Movies (Box 78, Folder 13)
        - Women Office Workers (Box 78, Folder 14)
        - Women's Action Alliance (Box 78, Folder 15)
        - Women's Center, Brooklyn College (Box 78, Folder 16)
        - Women's Experimental Theatre (Box 78, Folder 17)
        - Women's Interart Center (Box 78, Folder 18)
        - Women's Liberation Center of New York (Box 78, Folder 19)
        - Women's Martial Arts Center (Box 78, Folder 20)
        - Women's Martial Arts Union (Box 78, Folder 21)
        - Women's Survival Space (Box 79, Folder 1)
          [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Women's Survival Space]
        - Youth Action Program (Box 79, Folder 2)
      - Workshops and events
        - Alternatives for Women conference: agenda, publicity, correspondence, and evaluations, 1978-79 (Box 79, Folder 3-5)
        - Job Assistance workshop: publicity, 1979 (Box 79, Folder 6)
        - Job Fair: agenda and publicity, 1979 (Box 79, Folder 7)
        - Women's Funding Course: descriptions, proposal, correspondence, registration, budget, questionnaires, evaluations, and course material, 1980 (Box 79, Folder 8-17)
          [See also SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS-Women's Funding Coalition]
        - World of Work conference: agenda, publicity, correspondence, and planning materials, 1980 (Box 79, Folder 18-21)
        - World of Work conference (continued): questionnaires, registration, publicity, budget, handouts, and miscellaneous, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 1-5)
        - P.O.D Reunion: publicity, budget, planning materials, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous: certificates of appreciation, undated (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Job Development Program
      - General
        - Correspondence, 1979-81 (Box 80, Folder 8-10)
          [See also Project Open Doors]
        - CETA contract (Box 80, Folder 11)
        - Financial: budget and expenses (Box 80, Folder 12)
        - Meetings, 1980-81 (Box 80, Folder 13)
        - Proposals (Box 80, Folder 14-15)
        - Publicity: articles, statement, drafts for brochure and newsletter, business cards (Box 81, Folder 1)
        - Reports, 1980-81 (Box 81, Folder 2-3)
      - Staff: lists, manual, and activity logs, 1979-81 (Box 81, Folder 4-23)
      - Resources: forms, form letters, referrals, and printed material (Box 81, Folder 24-29)
      - Projects and services
        - Job clubs (Self-initiative employment project): proposals, correspondence, report, notes, and article, circa 1980-81 (Box 81, Folder 30-34)
        - Non-traditional Employment for Women (Women's Action Alliance program): proposal, correspondence, newsletter, printed material, workshop material, and resources, 1979-82, undated (Box 82, Folder 1-9)
      - VISTA Volunteers Recruitment Plan, 1979 (Box 10)
      - Research
        - Neighborhood analysis: correspondence, memoranda, notes, publicity, report, questionnaires, and background, 1978-80, undated (Box 82, Folder 11-14)
        - Job Market analysis: report, notes, and statistics, circa 1979-85 (Box 82, Folder 15-16)
      - Workshops and courses
        - General: questionnaire (Box 83, Folder 1)
        - Career planning course ("How to get the Job of your Dreams"), 1981 (Box 83, Folder 2)